

Phone: +49 1515 994 83 17 E-mail: a.d.ablov@gmail.com Github: aithub.com/AntonTeoretik LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/antonablov

WHO AM I?

I am student, currently finishing my masters. My main interests are math and programming. So, my skills correspond to these topics - I have an experience in various programming languages like C++, Haskell, Python, which I use to write some math (and other) projects, for example fluid modeling. I'm like to learn new things, especially if they are appliable and difficult simultaneously.

EXPERIENCE

Jul-Oct 2020 Haskell developer National center for continuous science education

I was a back-end developer in project «Hypermathica» (7.math.ru) – an online educational platform

for school children.

Jul 2019 -Methodist National center for continuous science education

I worked at content part for an online educational platform for school children (7.math.ru). Big part Jun 2020

of my work was also writing scripts on Python, which help to automatize different tasks.

Jun-Aug 2018 C++ developer (Internship) Fraunhofer Institute, Kaiserslautern

> I was part of a team that developed a program that simulated fiber structures for the needs of textile companies. The project was leaded by Dr Julia Orlik (julia.orlik@itwm.fraunhofer.de).

2016 - 2020 Mathematics and programming teacher Delta Summer Camp, Munich

delta.camp

For five years in Delta I taught several mathematical courses, such as «Introduction into the Group Theory», «Topology», «Stories about Infinite numbers», «Paradoxes of Set Theory» and etc. In addition, I made several projects with the students, written in various programming languages, for example:

- maze generator, written in Python;
- physical processes simulation (for instance 2D fluid flow) written in Python and C++;
- electromagnetic field visualization written in Haskell + OpenGl;

2015 - 2019 Mathematics teacher **Education Community "2x2"**

mathbabv.ru

I tell additional chapters of mathematics in the school, such as linear algebra, group theory and probability.

EDUCATION

2020-2022 Master's Degree The Rhenish Friedrich Wilhelm University of Bonn

mathematics.uni-bonn.de

My main field is algebraic topology and I am currently working on my master's thesis «Formality and coformality in rational homotopy theory». In addition I'm interested in algebra and logic, especially in homotopy type theory.

2015-2019 **Bachelor's Degree Lomonosov Moscow State University**

Faculty of Computational Mathematics and Cybernetics.

At the department of general mathematics, I was engaged in topological and metric spaces researches. My bachelor thesis is «Fixed points and coincidences of ultrametric and some quasiisometric spaces mappings».

LANGUAGES HOBBIES

C++ 17, Haskell, Python, My main hobbies are programming, teaching and music. As a program-Russian - native English - advanced Git, Latex

mer, I like sometimes to write small projects (on C++ or Haskell), related to math or gaming. As a teacher, I enjoy finding a way to tell people complicated things (like topology or algebra) in simple way. Finally, I am a musician and composer, I play piano, synths, and electric guitar.

For several years I played in hard/progressive rock band.